<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ayodeji Fabusuyi</title><link>https://thedejifab.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Ayodeji Fabusuyi</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© {year}</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 21:54:47 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thedejifab.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Why I enjoy watching plays</title><link>https://thedejifab.github.io/blog/on-first-impressions/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 21:54:47 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://thedejifab.github.io/blog/on-first-impressions/</guid><description>In the past year, I saw a lot of plays. I can’t remember them all, but I know the funniest play was An Order For Four at National Theatre Accra, and the best production I saw was Stranger Things on Broadway. I’m also lucky enough to live in London so most of my theatre outings have been fun - both on and off the West End.
There’s so many reasons I enjoy watching plays.</description></item><item><title>On first impressions</title><link>https://thedejifab.github.io/blog/on-first-impressions/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 21:54:47 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://thedejifab.github.io/blog/on-first-impressions/</guid><description>In my university days, there were people who were had good grades in their first year - either by luck, chance, hard work or whatever other factor there was. There were also people who had bad grades. Throughout my time at uni, it was more likely for the first group to continue on that track than it was for the second group to get on the good-grades track.
I imagine there’s a lot of reasons why that was the case - including the fact that the people who attained those grades by hard work were more likely to stay hardworking.</description></item><item><title>Switching vs Borrowing</title><link>https://thedejifab.github.io/blog/switching-vs-borrowing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 21:54:47 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://thedejifab.github.io/blog/switching-vs-borrowing/</guid><description>In my last post, I wrote about code switching, particularly the fact that code-switched Yoruba-English leads to significant information loss during translation. In trying to find a topic for my next post, the first thought was to explore theories surrounding the &amp;ldquo;information loss during translation&amp;rdquo;.
Could this loss be because Yoruba is a heavily diacritical language and many modern Yoruba speakers/writers are not big on diacritics? &amp;quot; or &amp;ldquo;Is less information lost if there&amp;rsquo;s a significantly greater proportion of one language over the other in code-switched expressions?</description></item><item><title>Why I'm doing this</title><link>https://thedejifab.github.io/blog/why-doing-this/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 21:54:47 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://thedejifab.github.io/blog/why-doing-this/</guid><description>In the final months of 2021, in search of a final year undergraduate thesis topic, especially one that would enable me to make a foray into the area of Natural Language Processing, I stumbled upon the concept of code-switching while reading Dan Jurafsky&amp;rsquo;s Speech and Language processing.
Code-switching involves alternating languages within an expression. At the simplest level, code-switching is what happens when a Nigerian says &amp;ldquo;bawo ni, what will you eat?</description></item></channel></rss>